<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Maz Blog</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2017-11-22T20:46:00-08:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Maz Ameli</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>SF Design Week interview, 2015</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/04/09/sf-design-week.html"/>
   <updated>2015-04-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/04/09/sf-design-week</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sf-skyline.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;SF skyline&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;this-interview-was-originally-published-in-a-slightly-different-form-on-sf-design-week-as-part-of-an-event-lookout-hosted-for-sf-design-week-2015&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This interview was originally published in a slightly different form on &lt;a href=&quot;http://sfdesignweek.org/interview-with-maz-ameli/&quot;&gt;SF Design Week&lt;/a&gt; as part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lookout.com/&quot;&gt;an event Lookout hosted&lt;/a&gt; for SF Design Week 2015.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SF Design Week: What are three things you believe in right now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maz Ameli: These days I really believe that product design is about forcing and facilitating conversations and decisions. To that end, I think right now designers must know how to prototype motion and interaction in order to enable a conversation around an artifact that’s truer to the actual experience. However, I also think that designers can’t possess the depth of insight and wealth of empathy that’s truly required in these kinds of conversations without unplugging more from the torrent of notifications, alerts, emails, and chatter of our digital lives — and instead spending more time in deep, sustained, contemplative thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SFDW: What motivates you to do great work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MA: The knowledge that a person is sitting down somewhere looking at what we’ve made and using it to try to get something done in her real life. I care about that person, and I want to do my very best to make her life easier, richer, and better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SFDW: What excites you about the future of design?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MA: I love that design has become more and more about people over the years — we’re focused on their needs, wants, problems, and desires. I think I’m most excited, though, about asking if what we are all designing, and the way we are designing, is good for people and for society at large. Technology is only going to become more ubiquitous globally — how do we want that world to look? I hope it’s a world where we’re more compassionate towards each other, more connected interpersonally, and more engaged with the very real problems that we face as a people and a planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SFDW: What project has had the biggest impact on you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MA: By far, working on Lookout’s newest enterprise product, Mobile Threat Protection, has pushed me the most to grow as a designer. The problems enterprises face, and the complexity of those problems, are both daunting and exhilarating as a product designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SFDW: What’s your “superpower?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MA: Our team of designers and researchers. We rely on each other to make ourselves better, smarter, and faster. I know we wouldn’t dig as deep, or explore as broadly and diligently if it weren’t for our willingness to push and prod and ask each other the really hard questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SFDW: Does Lookout have a mascot / sacred room / nicknames / anything quirky?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MA: Our team has a bizarre obsession with the stickers in the LINE app. I’ve also known one of our product designers to show up to work in lederhosen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SFDW: What keeps you up at night?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MA: Lately, my eight-month-old daughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SFDW: What are your tips for other designers out there who may just be getting started?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MA: Before you try to dive into solving the problem, make sure you’re solving the right problem. And always ask, “why?”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Designing for Elemental Human Problems</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/05/28/theft-alerts.html"/>
   <updated>2014-05-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2014/05/28/theft-alerts</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/alarm.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Alarm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, all of us at Lookout are tremendously excited to be announcing the launch of our new &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lookout.com/blog/2014/05/28/theft-alerts/&quot;&gt;Theft Alerts&lt;/a&gt; feature. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MrNamBui&quot;&gt;Nam Bui&lt;/a&gt; and the team have been working tirelessly on this for some time, and it’s great to see what they’ve come up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have Theft Alerts enabled, you’ll receive an email alert when Lookout detects a thief tampering with your phone. For example, the first thing a thief might do after stealing a phone is to power it down in order to prevent the owner from tracking it. With Theft Alerts, you’ll know when anything like this happens, and you’ll even get a photo from the stolen phone’s front-facing camera emailed to you, complete with a map of where your phone was when this happened. Armed with this info, and with the assistance of the authorities, hopefully you’ll be able to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dailystar.co.uk/news/latest-news/366409/Caught-in-a-flash-Mobile-app-captures-selfie-of-thief-and-is-shared-170-000-online&quot;&gt;catch the thief in the act&lt;/a&gt;. Theft Alerts also make Lookout’s other great features, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lookout.com/products/personal/android&quot;&gt;Locate, Backup, and Wipe&lt;/a&gt; even more useful, because now you’ll know better when to use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;designing-foremotion&quot;&gt;Designing for emotion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But beyond the great, fancy tech of Theft Alerts, if you abstract it to its essence, we’re actually solving the same kind of problem that a home security system does: “If someone is trying to break into my home, I want to know right away!” And really, this problem of guarding personal property goes back hundreds and hundreds of years: we used guard dogs to protect livestock, put alarm bells on doors, and employed soldiers to keep watch over our castles. So the reason Theft Alerts is compelling is not just because it’s using cool technology. It’s because Nam’s team designed it with a universal human experience in mind. Being robbed elicits all sorts of potent, primal emotions: rage, shock, grief — a sense of violation. (The first week that I moved to San Francisco a thief broke into my car, so I can attest to this.) But then catching a criminal in the act is also an emotionally charged experience. You feel euphoric, like justice has prevailed; you feel clever, and powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so Theft Alerts is more than just an email you get when someone, say, removes your SIM card. At a much more human level, Theft Alerts give you a sense of power and control that feels maybe a little bit like omniscience. You know everything that is happening to your phone, even when you’re not there. And there’s tremendous emotional potency in the promise that this will help you avoid all those powerful negative feelings in the event that your phone is stolen. Nobody wants to feel that they’re helpless, especially when something so sensitive and personal like their phone — and everything that’s on it — is put in jeopardy. But Theft Alerts help to put power back into your hands — you’ll know where your phone is, who’s messing with it, what to do to keep your information safe, and how to get the police involved. Even if your phone is gone for good, you’ll have the sense of closure that comes with knowing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lookout.com/features&quot;&gt;your information is safe&lt;/a&gt; and that the cops have a better chance of catching the crook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-heart-of-thematter&quot;&gt;The heart of the matter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of us in the design community have been talking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://abookapart.com/products/designing-for-emotion&quot;&gt;designing for emotion&lt;/a&gt; for some time now, and it’s been great to see that kind of thinking being poured into the design of Theft Alerts. As product designers, we have to remember that we’re not just designing cold vessels to deliver new technology to “users.” At our best, we’re endeavoring to solve authentic problems for actual people. And that kind of journey always begins by uncovering the underlying universal human problem underneath it all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
